CURRICULUM VITAE.

COSMAS AUGUSTINO BILLA P.O BOX 9057-00300. PHONE: (+254)729536851

EMAIL: augubilla100@gmail.com

BIO DATA

DATE OF BIRTH: 28TH FEBRUARY 1994

NATIONALITY: TANZANIAN PASSPORT NUMBER: AB731482 SEX: MALE **MARITAL STATUS:**

LANGUAGES: ENGLISH, SWAHILI **RELIGION:** CHRISTIAN, CATHOLIC.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

Aiming for a highly rewarding career, working with passion and becoming a valuable software developer who can create solutions to local and global problems. I love to teamwork with fellow developers, learn from them and help other individuals achieve their goals.

SINGLE.

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an open-minded individual who have passion in technology, electronics, machine learning and software development. I like working in a team, always willing to learn, can work independently and I have good time management skills. I have been coding for the last 1.5 years and I am confident in python and django but I have also work with php, codeigniter, yii, PhoneGap and bootstrap, and i can work with any programming language. In addition,I taught myself UI/UX, front end development, DevOps, Machine learning, wordpress, MySQL, MongoDB and PostgreSQL. I worked with several startups, I am co-founder of Iris innovations Inc.(irisinnovationsinc.com).

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

September 2014 - present: UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI.

Bsc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering.

January 2010-November 2013: OLOITOKITOK BOYS SECONDARY SCHOOL

Studied and successfully passed the Kenya

Certificate of Secondary Education and attained a

mean grade of B (plain).

January 2002- November 2009: D.E.B PRIMARY SCHOOL Studied and successfully passed the Kenya Certificate of Primary Education and attained a total of 320 marks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2016 to May 2017 - Software Developer at Boozeit
June 2017 to present - Software Developer, Co-founder at Iris Innovations Inc.
September 2017 to present - Software Developer at TaskJet
September 2017 to present - IT consultant to Skills for Nuba Mountains(skillsfornuba.org), Nuba Foundation(nubafoundation.org) and Hands of Brotherhood(handsofbrotherhood.org)

SKILLS

- Very honest and reliable
- Able to work under pressure
- Leadership skills
- Ready to learn new things
- Fast learner
- Programming skills in php, codeigniter, yii, mysql, twitter bootstrap

RESPONSIBILITIES HELD

2012 - 2013 Laboratory secretary

OLOITOKITOK BOYS SECONDARY SCHOOL

2011 - 2012 BARDEN POWELS House secretary

OLOITOKITOK BOYS SECONDARY SCHOOL

INTERESTS

- Nature scenery and hiking
- Swimming
- Watching
- Listening to music
- Travelling
- Physical exercise
- Valley ball

<u>REFERENCES</u>

MR SIMON NKURARU - OLOITOKITOK BOYS SECONDARY SCHOOL

HEADTEACHER

MR KARIUKI MAIN - BOOZEIT

CEO

MR LAZIM SULEIMAN - DIRECTOR

SKILLS FOR NUBA MOUNTAINS

MR FRANCIS KOME - NUBA FOUNDATION

CEO